Source --- https://devdocs.io/

These global properties return a simple value; they have no properties or methods.

    Infinity
    NaN
    undefined
    null literal

These global functions—functions which are called globally rather than on an object—directly return their 
results to the caller.

    eval()
    uneval()
    isFinite()
    isNaN()
    parseFloat()
    parseInt()
    decodeURI()
    decodeURIComponent()
    encodeURI()
    encodeURIComponent()
    escape()
    unescape()

These are the fundamental, basic objects upon which all other objects are based. This includes objects
 that represent general objects, functions, and errors.

    Object
    Function
    Boolean
    Symbol
    Error
    EvalError
    InternalError
    RangeError
    ReferenceError
    SyntaxError
    TypeError
    URIError

These are the base objects representing numbers, dates, and mathematical calculations.

    Number
    Math
    Date
These objects represent strings and support manipulating them.

    String
    RegExp


These objects represent collections of data which are ordered by an index value. This includes (typed) arrays and array-like constructs.

    Array
    Int8Array
    Uint8Array
    Uint8ClampedArray
    Int16Array
    Uint16Array
    Int32Array
    Uint32Array
    Float32Array
    Float64Array


These objects represent collections which use keys; these contain elements which are iterable in the order of insertion.

    Map
    Set
    WeakMap
    WeakSet


SIMD vector data types are objects where data is arranged into lanes.

    SIMD
    SIMD.Float32x4
    SIMD.Float64x2
    SIMD.Int8x16
    SIMD.Int16x8
    SIMD.Int32x4
    SIMD.Uint8x16
    SIMD.Uint16x8
    SIMD.Uint32x4
    SIMD.Bool8x16
    SIMD.Bool16x8
    SIMD.Bool32x4
    SIMD.Bool64x2


Structured data

These objects represent and interact with structured data buffers and data coded using JavaScript Object Notation (JSON).

    ArrayBuffer
    SharedArrayBuffer
    Atomics
    DataView
    JSON


Control abstraction objects

    Promise
    Generator
    GeneratorFunction
    AsyncFunction

Reflection

    Reflect
    Proxy


Internationalization

Additions to the ECMAScript core for language-sensitive functionalities.

    Intl
    Intl.Collator
    Intl.DateTimeFormat
    Intl.NumberFormat

WebAssembly

    WebAssembly
    WebAssembly.Module
    WebAssembly.Instance
    WebAssembly.Memory
    WebAssembly.Table
    WebAssembly.CompileError
    WebAssembly.LinkError
    WebAssembly.RuntimeError

Other

    arguments

Control flow

Block
    A block statement is used to group zero or more statements. The block is delimited by a pair of curly brackets.
break
    Terminates the current loop, switch, or label statement and transfers program control to the statement following the terminated statement.
continue
    Terminates execution of the statements in the current iteration of the current or labeled loop, and continues execution of the loop with the next iteration.
Empty
    An empty statement is used to provide no statement, although the JavaScript syntax would expect one.
if...else
    Executes a statement if a specified condition is true. If the condition is false, another statement can be executed.
switch
    Evaluates an expression, matching the expression's value to a case clause, and executes statements associated with that case.
throw
    Throws a user-defined exception.
try...catch
    Marks a block of statements to try, and specifies a response, should an exception be thrown. 



    Declarations

var
    Declares a variable, optionally initializing it to a value.
let
    Declares a block scope local variable, optionally initializing it to a value.
const
    Declares a read-only named constant. 



    Functions and classes

function
    Declares a function with the specified parameters.
function*
    Generator Functions enable writing iterators more easily.
async function
    Declares an async function with the specified parameters.
return
    Specifies the value to be returned by a function.
class
    Declares a class. 

    -------------
    Iterations

do...while
    Creates a loop that executes a specified statement until the test condition evaluates to false. The condition is evaluated after executing the statement, resulting in the specified statement executing at least once.
for
    Creates a loop that consists of three optional expressions, enclosed in parentheses and separated by semicolons, followed by a statement executed in the loop.
for each...in
    Iterates a specified variable over all values of object's properties. For each distinct property, a specified statement is executed.
for...in
    Iterates over the enumerable properties of an object, in arbitrary order. For each distinct property, statements can be executed.
for...of
    Iterates over iterable objects (including arrays, array-like objects, iterators and generators), invoking a custom iteration hook with statements to be executed for the value of each distinct property.
while
    Creates a loop that executes a specified statement as long as the test condition evaluates to true. The condition is evaluated before executing the statement. 


    --------------


    Iterations

do...while
    Creates a loop that executes a specified statement until the test condition evaluates to false. The condition is evaluated after executing the statement, resulting in the specified statement executing at least once.
for
    Creates a loop that consists of three optional expressions, enclosed in parentheses and separated by semicolons, followed by a statement executed in the loop.
for each...in
    Iterates a specified variable over all values of object's properties. For each distinct property, a specified statement is executed.
for...in
    Iterates over the enumerable properties of an object, in arbitrary order. For each distinct property, statements can be executed.
for...of
    Iterates over iterable objects (including arrays, array-like objects, iterators and generators), invoking a custom iteration hook with statements to be executed for the value of each distinct property.
while
    Creates a loop that executes a specified statement as long as the test condition evaluates to true. The condition is evaluated before executing the statement. 



    Others

debugger
    Invokes any available debugging functionality. If no debugging functionality is available, this statement has no effect.
export
    Used to export functions to make them available for imports in external modules, another scripts.
import
    Used to import functions exported from an external module, another script.
label
    Provides a statement with an identifier that you can refer to using a break or continue statement.

with
    Extends the scope chain for a statement. 



The filter() method returns a new array created from all elements
 that pass a certain test preformed on an original array.

 The map() method is used to apply a function on every element in an array.
  A new array is then returned.

  The reduce() method is used to apply a function to each element 
  in the array to reduce the array to a single value.

    



map,filter, reduce